RG 021:008, Norwich State Hospital
Connecticut State Library
Norwich State Hospital records
1904-1996
Connecticut State Library
Norwich State Hospital (Norwich, Conn.)
649 cubic feet
Norwich State Hospital operated from 1904 to 1996. Includes patient files, admission registers, medical staff records, and blueprints.
RG021_008
Multiple
Historical Note
The Norwich State Hospital for the Insane was established in 1904. About 1926 the name was changed to Norwich State Hospital. The hospital was administratively transferred to the new Dept. of Mental Health on Oct. 1, 1953. In 1961 the name was changed to Norwich Hospital. The hospital closed on October 10, 1996 and patients were transferred to Connecticut Valley Hospital in Middletown.
See also the.
Scope and Content
Series 1. Patients, 1904-1996, consist of patient files for discharged or deceased patients, 1904-1944, 1961, 1963, 1965-1966; admission registers, 1918-1995; and patient leaves and separations, 1984-1996. Series 2. Medical Staff Records, 1950-1972, consist solely of Lippitt Operating Room log books. Series 3. Blueprints, circa 1926-1954, consist of property plans and plot plans.
Arrangement
Arranged into three series: Patients, 1904-1996; Medical Staff Records, 1950-1972; and Blueprints, circa 1926-1954, undated.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Norwich State Hospital (Norwich, Conn.); Norwich State Hospital for the Insane (Norwich, Conn.)
Subjects:
Mental health facilities -- Connecticut; Psychiatric hospitals -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Blueprints; Medical records
Restrictions on Access
New Exemption: Public Act 11-242, section 37 amends subsection (b) (10) of Conn. Gen. Stat. sec. 1-210 and adds to the exemptions of the Freedom of Information Act any records created as a result of a doctor-patient or a therapist-patient relationship. This closure applies to all records listed below as Restricted.
Patients: Files continue to be made available to patients themselves upon reliable proof of identification which may be a current copy of a Connecticut driver's license with a photograph or current credit card with the patient's name on it.
Families: Section 52-146c of the Connecticut General Statutes allows "next of kin" the right to view records of a deceased patient who was also a relative.
Relatives of deceased patients should contact Assistant State Archivist Allen Ramsey by email at allen.ramsey@ct.gov or send a letter with the following information:
- Full name of the patient.
- Approximate years patient was treated at the hospital.
- Name, e-mail, and telephone of the requestor.
The State Archives will search for the folder and will report the results of the search to the requestor. If a file is found and the requestor wants to view or receive copies of the file, the following information must first be presented to the State Archivist:
- Proof of identity through a copy of a current Connecticut driver's license with a photograph or a copy of a current credit card with the requestor's name on it.
- Proof that the patient is deceased through a copy of a death certificate or obituary.
- Proof that the requestor is a "next of kin" to the deceased patient through a copy of a birth certificate, obituary with the name of the requestor mentioned as a survivor, or a signed and dated notarized statement of relationship to the patient.
Other Parties: According to the new exemption, medical records are closed to other parties.
Record Series Listed Below: Records listed below labeled as non-restricted or unrestricted are open to all researchers who have read the rules of use and signed the registration forms. Since these records are stored off site, they may not be available on the same day.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Patients, 1904-1996
  RESTRICTED
  - Patient records. Discharges, 1904-1944; 1961,; 1963,; 1965-1966; 191 cubic feet
    These records represent only a sampling since the State Archives did not have room to take in more.
    Patient files organized chronologically by discharge/death dates. Dates are inclusive.
    - 1993-008, 17 cubic feet
      - Male patients
        - Aaronwicz-Battista, 1909-1940 (Box 1)
        - Batty-Brekovsky, 1909-1940 (Box 2)
        - Brennan-Carmody, 1909-1940 (Box 3)
        - Carnell-Clark, G., 1909-1940 (Box 4)
        - Clark, J.-Coughlan, 1909-1940 (Box 5)
        - Coughlin-Dawley, 1909-1940 (Box 6)
        - Dawson-Detar, 1909-1940 (Box 7)
      - Female patients
        - Aaronson-Baine, M., 1909-1940 (Box 8)
        - Baker-Belzer, 1909-1940 (Box 9)
        - Benchley-Bradshaw, A., 1909-1940 (Box 10)
        - Bradshaw, E.-Burgharti, 1909-1940 (Box 11)
        - Burke-Chamberlain, M., 1909-1940 (Box 12)
        - Chamberlain, N.-Cooly, 1909-1940 (Box 13)
        - Cooney-Crowley, 1909-1940 (Box 14)
        - Crumb-Denicolantonio, 1909-1940 (Box 15)
        - Denison-Dixon, 1909-1940 (Box 16)
        - Dlugolecki-Donegan, 1909-1940 (Box 17)
    - 1993-020, 174 cubic feet
      - Male patients
        - A-Bem, 1961 (Box 454)
        - Ben-Bo, 1961 (Box 455)
        - Br-Bz, 1961 (Box 456)
        - Ca-Ce, 1961 (Box 457)
        - Ch-Con, 1961 (Box 458)
        - Coo-Del, 1961 (Box 459)
        - Dem-Do, 1961 (Box 460)
        - Dr-Fi, 1961 (Box 461)
        - Fi-Gif, 1961 (Box 462)
        - Gil-Gz, 1961 (Box 463)
        - Ha-Ho, 1961 (Box 464)
        - Hr-J, 1961 (Box 465)
        - Ka-Kri, 1961 (Box 466)
        - Kro-li, 1961 (Box 467)
        - Lo-Man, 1961 (Box 468)
        - Mar-Men, 1961 (Box 469)
        - Mer-Mon, 1961 (Box 470)
        - Moo-Mz, 1961 (Box 471)
        - Na-Ol, 1961 (Box 472)
        - On-Pi, 1961 (Box 473)
        - Pl-Ra, 1961 (Box 474)
        - Re-Ru, 1961 (Box 475)
        - Ry-Se, 1961 (Box 476)
        - Sh-Sm, 1961 (Box 477)
        - Sn-Te, 1961 (Box 478)
        - Th-Va, 1961 (Box 479)
        - Vi-We, 1961 (Box 480)
        - Wh-Z, 1961 (Box 481)
      - Female patients
        - Don-Dow, 1904-1941 (Box 37)
        - Doy-Dui, 1904-1941 (Box 38)
        - Dug-D, 1904-1941 (Box 39)
        - Duv-Eds, 1904-1941 (Box 40)
        - Edw-Eng, 1904-1941 (Box 41)
        - Enn-Fai, 1904-1941 (Box 42)
        - Far-Fen, 1904-1941 (Box 43)
        - Fer-Fit, 1904-1941 (Box 44)
        - Fitzp-Fo, 1904-1941 (Box 45)
        - Fol-Foy, 1904-1941 (Box 46)
        - Fra-Fro, 1904-1941 (Box 47)
        - Fry-Gal, 1904-1941 (Box 48)
        - Gams-Gel, 1904-1941 (Box 49)
        - Gem-Gil, 1904-1941 (Box 50)
        - Gio-Gof, 1904-1941 (Box 51)
        - Goli-Gnn, 1904-1941 (Box 52)
        - Gran-Gre, 1904-1941 (Box 53)
        - Gren-Gue, 1904-1941 (Box 54)
        - Gui-Hal, 1904-1941 (Box 55)
        - Hall-Han, 1904-1941 (Box 56)
        - Hans-Hatl, 1904-1941 (Box 57)
        - Har-Hay, 1904-1941 (Box 58)
        - Hen-Hic, 1904-1941 (Box 59)
        - Hob-Hol, 1904-1941 (Box 60)
        - Hop-Hor, 1904-1941 (Box 61)
        - Hub-Hur, 1904-1941 (Box 62)
        - Hy-Jac, 1904-1941 (Box 63)
        - Jam-Jo, 1904-1941 (Box 64)
        - Joh-Jon, 1904-1941 (Box 65)
        - Joy-Kal, 1904-1941 (Box 66)
        - Kant-Kea, 1904-1941 (Box 67)
        - Kei-Kell, 1904-1941 (Box 68)
        - Kein-Kinde, 1904-1941 (Box 69)
        - King-Knox, 1904-1941 (Box 70)
        - Ko-Koz, 1904-1941 (Box 71)
        - Kr-Lada, 1904-1941 (Box 72)
        - Ladd-Lap, 1904-1941 (Box 73)
        - Lar-Leb, 1904-1941 (Box 74)
        - Lec-Les, 1904-1941 (Box 75)
        - Let-Linc, 1904-1941 (Box 76)
        - Lind-Lon, 1904-1941 (Box 77)
        - Loo-Lun, 1904-1941 (Box 78)
        - Lus-Mac, 1904-1941 (Box 79)
        - Macr-Mal, 1904-1941 (Box 80)
        - Mal-Map, 1904-1941 (Box 81)
        - Mar-Mart, 1904-1941 (Box 82)
        - Mart-Maz, 1904-1941 (Box 83)
        - MCc-Mcd, 1904-1941 (Box 84)
        - Mcdo-Mckl, 1904-1941 (Box 85)
        - Mcl-Men, 1904-1941 (Box 86)
        - Mer-Mille, 1904-1941 (Box 87)
        - Mille-Moll, 1904-1941 (Box 88)
        - Mollo-Moran, 1904-1941 (Box 89)
        - Moran-Mort, 1904-1941 (Box 90)
        - Mose-F. Murphy, 1904-1941 (Box 91)
        - M. Murphy-Nash, 1904-1941 (Box 92)
        - Nash-Nic, 1904-1941 (Box 93)
        - Nie-Nut, 1904-1941 (Box 94)
        - Nye-O'C, 1904-1941 (Box 95)
        - O'D-Ost, 1904-1941 (Box 96)
        - Osu-Palm, 1904-1941 (Box 97)
        - Palo-Pat, 1904-1941 (Box 98)
        - Pau-Plm, 1904-1941 (Box 99)
        - Pend-Pete, 1904-1941 (Box 100)
        - Pet-Pie, 1904-1941 (Box 101)
        - Pig-Pl, 1904-1941 (Box 102)
        - Poi-Pow, 1904-1941 (Box 103)
        - Prat-Qui, 1904-1941 (Box 104)
        - Quin-Ra, 1904-1941 (Box 105)
        - Rea-Rev, 1904-1941 (Box 106)
        - Rey-Rie, 1904-1941 (Box 107)
        - Ril-Rol, 1904-1941 (Box 108)
        - Robs-Ror, 1904-1941 (Box 109)
        - Ros-Rug, 1904-1941 (Box 110)
        - Ruk-Saj, 1904-1941 (Box 111)
        - Sal-Saon, 1904-1941 (Box 112)
        - Saut-Schul, 1904-1941 (Box 113)
        - Schum-See, 1904-1941 (Box 114)
        - Seg-She, 1904-1941 (Box 115)
        - M. Shea-Shu, 1904-1941 (Box 116)
        - Si-Sk, 1904-1941 (Box 117)
        - Slo-Smith, 1904-1941 (Box 118)
        - G. Smith-Sny, 1904-1941 (Box 119)
        - Sob-Spe, 1904-1941 (Box 120)
        - Spi-Ste, 1904-1941 (Box 121)
        - Sten-Stra, 1904-1941 (Box 122)
        - Stra-Sum, 1904-1941 (Box 123)
        - Swa-Tan, 1904-1941 (Box 124)
        - Tap-Thomas, 1904-1941 (Box 125)
        - Thomas-Toom, 1904-1941 (Box 126)
        - Tor-Tre, 1904-1941 (Box 127)
        - Tut-Va, 1904-1941 (Box 128)
        - Vas-Vz, 1904-1941 (Box 129)
        - Wa-Wanc, 1904-1941 (Box 130)
        - Wann-Wl, 1904-1941 (Box 131)
        - Wein-West, 1904-1941 (Box 132)
        - Wid-Whi, 1904-1941 (Box 133)
        - Wild-Wilson, 1904-1941 (Box 134)
        - Wilt-Won, 1904-1941 (Box 135)
        - Woo-Yanz, 1904-1941 (Box 136)
        - Yo-Z, 1904-1941 (Box 137)
        - A-Ce, 1942 (Box 138)
        - Ch-Fl, 1942 (Box 139)
        - Fr-K, 1942 (Box 140)
        - La-N, 1942 (Box 141)
        - Ows-Sop, 1942 (Box 142)
        - Mary-Young, 1942 (Box 143)
        - Adams-Case, 1943 (Box 144)
        - Ch-E, 1943 (Box 145)
        - F-Ha, 1943 (Box 146)
        - Ha-Ma, 1943 (Box 147)
        - Mc-R, 1943 (Box 148)
        - Ra-Th, 1943 (Box 149)
        - Ti-Z, 1943 (Box 150)
        - A-Bo, 1944 (Box 151)
        - Br-Do, 1944 (Box 152)
        - Dr-Ha, 1944 (Box 153)
        - He-L, 1944 (Box 154)
        - Ma-Pe, 1944 (Box 155)
        - Ph-St, 1944 (Box 156)
        - Su-Z, 1944 (Box 157)
        - A-Ba, 1961 (Box 394)
        - Be-Bri, 1961 (Box 395)
        - Bro-Cha, 1961 (Box 396)
        - Che-Cou, 1961 (Box 397)
        - Cre-De, 1961 (Box 398)
        - Do-Ez, 1961 (Box 399)
        - Fa-Ga, 1961 (Box 400)
        - Ge-Gz, 1961 (Box 401)
        - Ha-Hl, 1961 (Box 402)
        - Ho-Joh, 1961 (Box 403)
        - Joh-Ko, 1961 (Box 404)
        - Kr-Le, 1961 (Box 405)
        - Li-Man, 1961 (Box 406)
        - Mar-Man, 1961 (Box 407)
        - Mck-Moo, 1961 (Box 408)
        - Mor-Nc, 1961 (Box 409)
        - No-Oz, 1961 (Box 410)
        - Pa-Q, 1961 (Box 411)
        - Ra-Rz, 1961 (Box 412)
        - Sa-Sha, 1961 (Box 413)
        - She-Sti, 1961 (Box 414)
        - Sto-Th, 1961 (Box 415)
        - Ti-Wa, 1961 (Box 416)
        - We-Wi, 1961 (Box 417)
        - Wo-Z, 1961 (Box 418)
    - 2000-015, 442 cubic feet
      - 1904-1944, 1963, 1965-1966 (Box 459-900)
        Box 900 contains Personnel Records, circa 1943.
  - Admission registers, 1918-1995; 2010-012
    Volume(s) covering 1942 July 1 - 1949 June 30 were not transferred to the State Archives.
    - 1918 July 30 - 1923 June 30, 1 volume (Volume Item 1)
      Back of volume: Criminally insane, 1919 January 28 - 1924 January 3.
      Spine states: State Hospital for the Insane
    - 1923 July 1 - 1927 June 20, 1 volume (Volume Item 2)
      Back of volume: Criminally insane, 1924 January 3 - 1933 May 12.
    - 1918 July 30 - 1923 June 30, 1 volume (Volume Item 3)
    - 1931 April 8 - 1934 September 29, 1 volume (Volume Item 4)
      Back of volume: Criminally insane, 1933 May 17 - 1938 October 24
    - 1934 September 30 - 1938 March 1, 1 volume (Volume Item 5)
    - 1938 March 4 - 1942 June 30, 1 volume (Volume Item 6)
    - 1949 July 1 - 1962 July 25, 1 volume (Volume Item 7)
    - 1962 July 26 - 1967 June 30, 1 volume (Volume Item 8)
    - 1967 July 1 - 1970 December 30, 1 volume (Volume Item 9)
    - 1971 January 1 - 1974 June 30, 1 volume (Volume Item 10)
    - 1974 July 1 - 1977 June 30, 1 volume (Volume Item 11)
    - 1977 July 1 - 1981 June 30, 1 volume (Volume Item 12)
    - 1981 July 1 - 1984 June 30, 1 volume (Volume Item 13)
    - 1984 July 1 - 1989 June 30, 1 volume (Volume Item 14)
    - 1989 July 1 - 1995 December 31, 1 volume (Volume Item 15)
  - Patient leaves and separations, 1984-1996
    - 1984 June - 1989 June (Box 16)
    - 1989 July - 1996 October (Box 17)
- Series 2. Medical Staff Records, 1950-1972
  - Lippitt Operating Room log books
    - 1950 January - 1961 December (Volume Item 18)
    - 1961 December - 1967 August (Volume Item 19)
    - 1967 August - 1972 February (Volume Item 20)
- Series 3. Blueprints, circa 1926-1954, undated
  - circa 1926-1954, 2006-037; 3 cubic feet (2 poster boxes) (Box 1-2)
    UNRESTRICTED
  - undated, T000708; 4 cubic feet (2 oversize bundles)
    RESTRICTED due to condition. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.